A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Early Files, Personal and Professional papers, RG 1 FA1858
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Early Files, Personal and Professional papers, RG 1
1761-1999
1910-1945
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
Rockefeller, Mary French (1910-1997)
FA1858
8.36 Cubic Feet 9.5 letter-size document boxes, 7 legal-size document boxes, 1 oversized flat box (11" x 17"), 2 flat file folders (M, L).
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted.
Material in the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers relating to communications with his immediate family, his personal finances, and other intra-family matters, is restricted until 2029, twenty years from the date of gift.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The executors of the Laurance S. Rockefeller Estate donated these records to the Rockefeller Archive Center by deed of gift in January 2009.
Scope and Contents
RG 1 of the Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR) papers consists primarily of personal papers gathered from his Kent House (Tarrytown) and 834 Fifth Avenue (NY) residences. The collection includes LSR's correspondence with his parents, friends, and family from childhood into adulthood; schooling, college, law-school, and early professional papers; records of his naval service and aviation interests; wedding and engagement records; travel records; and some personal financial records.
While most of the papers come from LSR's home, they were created and maintained at different times and places. His mother, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR), kept some of these papers, which came to LSR only after her death in 1948. The collection also includes a few materials of a more historical or antiquarian interest.
LSR's correspondence may seem particularly illuminating of the social life of a privileged college student, but the correspondence also provides insight into his upbringing and descriptions of more formative experiences such as LSR's participation in the Grenfell expedition to Labrador in 1929, the Princeton Geology Trip in 1930, and his trip to Jasper National Park in 1932 as a wildlife photographer for American Nature Association founder Arthur N. Pack.
As a lieutenant and then lieutenant commander in the Navy from 1942-1945, LSR was assigned to the Navy's Bureau of Aeronautics, where he served as assistant head of the Aircraft Production Section.
Arrangement
The Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR) papers, RG 1, Early Files, Personal and Professional Papers, draws together materials from several accessions, in whole or part, of personal papers from LSR's homes. Unlike LSR's general files or other papers, these materials were not organized or maintained by the Rockefeller Family Office.
Materials from these accessions have been grouped together in a single arrangement generally by subject or document type, and then, imperfectly, by date. While the materials are arranged in a single series, files pertaining to LSR's naval service are distinct in subject and nature from the other files.
- Letters from Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR) to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR), circa 1912 - 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters from Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR) to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR) - Lock of Baby Hair, circa May 1912 (Box 1, Folder 1 A)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted - Preservation Concerns
  Scope and Contents
  Lock of LSR's hair, enclosed in undated letter from LSR (i.e., from his nurse) to AAR.
- Letters from Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR) to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR) and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. (JDR Jr.), 1920-1921, 1923-1929 (Box 1, Folder 2-9)
- Letters from Laurance S. Rockefeller to AAR and JDR, Jr., 1930-1933 (Box 2, Folder 10-14)
  Folders include photos and brochure concerning Princeton Summer Camp (1930) and LSR's letters on the Princeton Geology trip (1930); plus his letters from Europe in 1931, and from his Jasper National Park trip in 1932.
- Letters from Laurance S. Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller (MFR) to AAR and JDR, Jr., 1934-1937 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  Includes letters from Europe in 1935 and 1937 (including visit to Hamburg zoo and meeting with [Alvar Aalto]).
- Letters from Laurance S. Rockefeller and MFR to AAR and JDR, Jr., 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Letters from Europe in 1935 and 1937 (including visit to Hamburg zoo and meeting with [Alvar Aalto]).
- Letters from Laurance S. Rockefeller and MFR to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (AAR), circa 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Letters mainly from Mary French Rockefeller.
- Letters from JDR, Jr. and AAR to Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR), 1915, 1917, 1930-1933 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence between JDR, Jr., AAR, and LSR and MFR, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Correspondence between JDR, Jr. and Mary French Rockefeller, 1934-1937 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence between JDR, Jr., AAR, and LSR and MFR, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Correspondence between JDR, Jr. and LSR and MFR, 1941-1960 (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
- Correspondence between JDR, Jr., AAR, and LSR and MFR (Box 3, Folder 21A - 22A)
  Restricted - LSR Financial Information - Open in 2029.
  Restricted - Living Rockefeller family - Personal - Restricted for Life.
  File contains redacted or separated items from Box 3, Folders 21 and 22.
- Correspondence with JDR, Jr. and Martha Baird Rockefeller, 1951, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Birthday, Allowance, Wedding, and Other Gifts from JDR, Jr. to LSR, 1931-1934 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Includes letter from LSR to JDR, Jr., May 1931.
- JDR, Jr. Gifts to LSR, 1946-1952 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Lucy Truman Aldrich Correspondence, 1930s-1940s, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Also includes letter from Nelson A. Rockefeller to Lucy Truman Aldrich, January 14, 1949, and letter from John D.Rockefeller, Jr., March 15, 1949, enclosing group photos of JDR, Jr. and his sons, and of Babs and her sisters-in-law, 1949. Also includes earlier formal photo of AAR with her daughter and daughters-in-law.
- Letters from Mary Adeline (Madeline) Prentice to LSR, 1928-1932 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Letters from Abby "Babs" Rockefeller to LSR and MFR, 1925, 1929, 1932-1933,1938, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Abby "Babs" Rockefeller - Pressed Flowers from Her Wedding (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Restricted - Preservation Concerns.
  Note on envelope: To go back in Bible from Babs wedding.
- Letters from David Milton and H.L. Bowdoin, 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Concerning investment in Bowdoin's expedition to salvage the liner "Merida."
- Correspondence between David Rockefeller and LSR, 1920-1933 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Letters from John D. Rockefeller to LSR, 1923-1925, 1930, 1932, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Includes photo card of JDR on his 91st birthday; JDR letter concerning his wedding gift to LSR and MFR, July 26, 1934.
- Letters from John D. Rockefeller, 3rd, to LSR, 1923-1934, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Includes February 14, 1923, letter from JDR 3 to NAR. Also includes invitation to JDR 3's wedding to Blanchette Ferry Hooker, November 11, 1932.
- Letters from David Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, 3rd, to AAR and JDR, Jr., 1927-1928 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Letters from Nelson A. Rockefeller to LSR, 1925 - circa 1932 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Letters from Nelson A. Rockefeller and Mary Tod Clark Rockefeller to LSR, 1929-1934 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Campaign and Letters to LSR and MFR, 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Includes photos of NAR at the San Gennaro Festival in New York, in 1958.
- Letters from Winthrop Rockefeller to LSR, circa 1921-1934 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  Includes letter from NAR to Winthrop Rockefeller, May 23, 1933.
- Friends and Associates Correspondence (A - Day), 1921, 1928-1933 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  Includes Atta Albertson; Henry Alpern; Edith J. Baerwald; Pierre Benoit, 1926-1928 (had been LSR's French tutor; includes photos); Beta Rothafel Bijur; Betty Nugent Blackiston and H.C. (Harry) Blackiston, Jr.; Thatcher Brown concerning Helen Brown; Wilhelmus (Bill) b. Bryan, Jr. and Katharine (Kit) MacKenty Bryan; Otis W. Caldwell; Marion Rumsey Cartier; Zechariah Chafee, Jr.; Chan Chunman, 1921 (copy of letter concerning JDR Jr. and AAR's trip to China); Lucy Anne Colpitts; "Cally"; J. Lionberger Davis; George Vietor Davis; Joseph P. Day.
- Friends and Associates Correspondence (De - F), 1923, 1928-1934 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  Includes: Frank Debenham and Dorothy Lempriere Debenham; George and Margaret Strong DeCuevas; James C. Donnell, Jr. and Dolly Devine Donnell; Elizabeth Douglas; E.B.M. "Emilie"; Fannie Evans; F.C.W. "Faith"; James L. Faunce; Abraham Flexner; Mignon E. (Miggs) Foerderer; Harry Emerson Fosdick; Raymond B. Fosdick; F.F.H. "Fran"; Helen Francis; John French; Rhoda Walker French; Elisha M. Friedman.
- Friends and Associates Correspondence (G-I), 1925, 1927-1933 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  Includes: Maud Ely Gibbons; G.D. Oswald Gockler /Daniel Gauclair; Harmon Goldstone; Albert T. Gould; Sir Wilfred Grenfell; Robert H. Gumbel; Eugene Henderson, Hampton Institute; Anita Candler Hinckley (including a request for help with a term paper on Diego Rivera, 1933?); Don [Hooker?]; Russell Houghton Hooker.
- Friends and Associates Correspondence (J-O), 1921, 1928-1933 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  Includes: Phil Jessup; Maggi (Margaret) Shea Johnson; Rufus M. Jones; "Kathleen," 1929; Lillian M. Kline; Michael Kopliner; Susan Kronthal; B. Lamb; "Lily"; Jere Lord; Donald B. MacMillan; "Marty"; Otakar Matousek; Cyrus H. McCormick; Harold McCormick; McCormick, Muriel; "Mizzie" or "Miggie" (MMR); Peggy [de Morinni?]; Margaret Elizabeth ("Betty") Nichols; Jane Northrup.
- Friends and Associates Correspondence (P-R), 1930-1934, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  Inclues: Arthur N. Pack and Eleanor Brown (Brownie) Pack, 1932-1934; Lee Palfrey; "Pauline"; Gertrude Peabody; Bill Piel; John Wolcott Porter; Betty Pratt; Natalie Pulsifer; Dr. Paul Ramdohr; E. Lansing Ray, Jr.; Henri Reynier; Will Rogers (copy, undated); Frin [Rousmaniere]; Polly Rousmaniere.
- Friends and Associates Correspondence (S-Z), 1924, 1927-1933, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  Elizabeth (Betty) Saltonstall; Reverend M. Huyett Sangree ("San"); Hans Schneiderhoehn; Elizabeth Hibben Scoon; J. Lyndon Shanley; Charles Sheeler; Don Sheldon; Dorothea K. Shipway; "Skillet"; H. Alexander Smith; Eleanor A. Smyth; Frederic Soldwedel; "Susan" [?], and Anne Sibley; "Teddy"; Andre Trocme, 1928; "Scally" [Challis Walker]; Robert R. Wicks; Lillie Distler Woelfkin (Mrs. Cornelius Woelfkin); Wallace F. Worthley, 1924; Y. Yishikawa.
- Friends and Associates Correspondence (General), 1929-1934, 1940, 1944-1979, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  Miscellaneous later correspondence, mainly from 1944-1949. Includes, among others: telegrams from Pete Kriendler and Jacob Javits, 1974; Harper Woodward; Horace Albright, 1963; Robert Trent Jones, 1963, with 2 snapshots; Peggy Rockefeller; A. K. Morgan, 1945, 1956, and map of Palisades Interstate Park; Bill Duncan, 1947; Mary M. B. French, 1945, concerning Zoological Society Meeting; Childs Frick, 1945; George D. Owen, Union Church, 1944; Jesse H. Knight, 1945, concerning business interests in Colombia; Lewis Valentine letter of introduction for LSR and MFR, 1940; John French, 1947, 1979; Wallace Harrison, undated notes; Donal O'Brien to LSR, 1999, enclosing letter from Nelson A. Rockefeller to Thomas Debevoise, 1952, concerning sale of Hills Realty stock to the Brothers' generation. Also includes a few unidentified telegrams and notes, 1929-1934.
- Letters from Mary French to LSR, circa 1928-1932, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 48-50)
  Restricted - LSR Estate - Open in 2029
- Letters to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller on the Birth of LSR, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 51)
- LSR Childhood Health Record (Nurse's Book), 1910-1926 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  Includes a growth chart for David Rockefeller, 1915-1917.
- LSR Expense Account Books (4 Volumes), 1920-1929 (Box 6, Folder 53-56)
  Volumes for 1920-1924, 1924-1926, 1926 September - 1927 January, and 1927-1929.
- LSR Expense Account Book, 1930-1934 (Box 7, Folder 57)
- Activities and Interests, 1933-1939 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  Brochures, clippings, correspondence. Includes: Architects' Emergency Committee's Fund; letter concerning Ansel Adams photos of Laboratory of Anthropology at Santa Fe, 1933; Princeton-Yenching Foundation, 1934; Fosdick clippings, 1934; National Championship Competition for Big Game Hunters, 1937-1938; English-Speaking Union, 1938; unidentified invitation list; World Wide Broadcasting Foundation, 1938; World's Fair Map, 1939.
- Apartments - 115 East 67th Street - Floor Plan (Box 7, Folder 59)
- Automobiles and License, 1927-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
  Includes photo of a bronze "Panther" radiator cap, made for LSR.
- Camp Merryweather Brochure, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Artwork and Early Schoolwork, 1913-1922 (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Education - Religion Schoolwork (Box 7, Folder 63)
- Education - Schoolwork, 1920-1927, undated (Box 7, Folder 64-66)
  The folder for 1926 (folder 65) includes three manuscript reports (two with illustrations): A Photographers Visit to France; Photography Report - Types of Cameras; and Chemistry in Photography.
- Education - College Entrance Examination Board, Requirements (Pamphlet), 1928 (Box 7, Folder 67)
- Education - Lincoln School - General, 1917-1928 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  Includes report cards, programs, rosters, and correspondence.
- Education - Lincoln School - Crests, 1920s (Box 7, Folder 69)
  Two felt crests with Lincoln School insignia.
- Education - Script, "A Minuet," by Louis N. Parker (Box 7, Folder 70)
  Play published circa 1922. From a Lincoln School performance or from one at Princeton?
- Education - Pine Lodge School, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  Brochures from the Spring Gymkhana, April 30, 1921.
- Education - Roger Ascham School, 1915-1917 (Box 7, Folder 72)
- Education - Princeton University - General, 1928-1932 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  Clippings, correspondence, articles, grade reports. Includes Ivy Club membership booklet, 1928-1929.
- Education - Princeton University - Commencement, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 74)
- Education - Princeton University - Philosophy Alumni Association, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 75)
- Education - Hun School, Princeton - Tutoring Notes (3 Folders), circa 1929-1931 (Box 8, Folder 76-78)
  LSR notebooks on topics in Philosophy, and science flashcards.
- Harvard Law School - General, 1932-1934 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  Includes letters from LSR to Guy Holliday, secretary of Harvard Law School, and from Henry Alpern to LSR, August 1934, concerning his continuing at the Law School.
- Harvard Law School - Directories, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 80)
- Harvard Law School - Case Notes, circa 1932-1934 (Box 8, Folder 81)
- Harvard Law School - Examinations, 1933-1935 (Box 8, Folder 82)
- Harvard Law School - Review Notes (Agency), circa 1932-1935 (Box 8, Folder 83)
- Harvard Law School - Review Notes (Civil Procedure) (2 Folders), circa 1932-1935 (Box 8, Folder 84-85)
- Harvard Law School - Review Notes (Conveyancing), circa 1932-1935 (Box 8, Folder 86)
- Harvard Law School - Review Notes (Evidence), 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 87)
- Harvard Law School - Review Notes (Property I), circa 1932-1935 (Box 9, Folder 88)
- Harvard Law School - Texts and Notes, 1932-1935 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  Introduction to The Law of Real Property, by Harry A. Bigelow, with LSR marginal notes.
- Harvard Law School - Ames Competition Pamphlets, 1932-1933 (Box 9, Folder 90)
- Harvard Law School - Scott Law Club - Ames Competition Briefs (5 Folders), 1932-1934 (Box 9, Folder 91-95)
- Milbank, Tweed, Hope and Webb Employment (2 Folders), 1933 (Box 9, Folder 96-97)
- Medical and Health, 1929-1933, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  Includes exercises and golf booklet.
- Medical, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 98A)
  Restricted - Medical record - Open in 2029
- Institute of Pacific Relations Conference, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  LSR attended the conference in Banff, August 14-26, 1933, as a recorder for the U.S. group.
- Princeton Summer Camp, 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 100)
- Princeton Westminster Foundation, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  Correspondence from David H. McAlpin III and W.B. (Bill) Bryan, and reports.
- Rockefeller Center, 1932, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  The Story of Rockefeller Center (1932), and Rockefeller Center Outing, 1938.
- Speeches (LSR) - United Service Organization (USO) Fundraising - Tarrytown, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 103)
- Speeches - Eddie Rickenbacker, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  Speeches at the First Annual Dinner of the Wings Club, March 22, 1944; and to the American War Dads, Kansas City, MO, May 30, 1944 ("America - Wake Up!").
- Trips - Western Trips - Itineraries, 1924, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 105)
- Trips - European Trip Itinerary, 1927 June 18 - July 27 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  JDR Jr., AAR, and five sons. Travel through France.
- Trips - Great Lakes Trip Itinerary, 1928 June 25 - July 4 (Box 10, Folder 107)
- Trips - European Trips, 1931-1932 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  LSR trip with Vietor Davis, 1931 (includes international passport and calling cards); itinerary for proposed trip to Scandinavia, Eastern Europe, and Russia, with Lansing Ray and Don Hooker, 1932 (LSR did not join the 1932 trip).
- Trips - Jasper National Park, Canada, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  Clippings. Trip to film wildlife for the American Nature Association, with Arthur and Eleanor B. Pack, W. B. and Kit Bryan, and Robert Wood and Maggi Johnson.
- Letters to LSR on His Engagement, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  Includes,among other responses, letters from Nelson A. Rockefeller, and LSR response, June 15 and July 17, 1934; and letter from Winthrop Rockefeller, July 15, 1934. Also includes a wedding photo.
- Letters to LSR on His Engagement, and Wedding Responses, 1934 July-August (Box 10, Folder 111)
  Includes some notes to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
- Letters to Mary French on Her Engagement, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 112)
- LSR and MFR Wedding Invitation, Announcement, and Lists, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 113)
- LSR and MFR Marriage Certificate and Service Booklet, 1934 August 15 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  Leather-bound booklet of the marriage service, signed by LSR, MFR, and attendants, and with marriage certificate signed by the officiant.
- Clippings - LSR and MFR Engagement and Wedding, 1934 July-August (Box 10, Folder 115)
  File contains a selection from multiple press service clippings sent by Ivy Lee.
- LSR and MFR Wyoming Trip, 1934 September (Box 10, Folder 116)
  File contains a Grand Teton National Park brochure and LSR's hunting permits.
- Financial Materials - LSR Annual Financial Statements, 1929-1931 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  Restricted - LSR Financial Informtaion - Open in 2029
- Financial Materials - Chase National Bank - Checkbook, 1933 May-November (Box 11, Folder 118)
- Financial Materials - Investments (2 folders), 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 119 - 120)
  Restricted - LSR Financial Information - Open in 2029
- Christmas Cards to LSR, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 121)
- LSR and MFR Family - Children's Cards to JDR Jr. and AAR, 1940s, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 122)
- Letter from LSR to His Daughters (Copy), 1944 May (Box 11, Folder 123)
- LSR and MFR - Twenty-Fifth Wedding Anniversary, 1959 August 15 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  Celebration at Woodstock - Acknowledgments and thank-yous.
- Visit of H.R.H. Prince Henry of Prussia to New York City, 1902 February 25-26 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  Invitations to John D. Rockefeller for ceremonies, dinner, and breakfast with the Prince; program booklet identifying the breakfast guests.
- Walter McClintock to John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1929 September 24 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  Enclosing photos of members of the Blackfoot Tribe. The photographs are found in LSR photographs, Photo Files, FA1128, Box O 2.
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Invitation List for Musicale, 1936 February 17 (Box 12, Folder 126)
  AAR and JDR Jr. hosted a Musicale at their home in honor of daughters-in-law Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller and Mary French Rockefeller. See also program and correspondence in LSR papers, RG 2 (FA433), series 6, box 50, folder 673.
- Mount Desert Larger Parish, Sky Pilot's Log, 1938-1940 (Box 12, Folder 128)
  Parish brochure and program review.
- Mount Hope Farm (Williamstown, MA) - Pamphlets, 1928, undated (Box 12, Folder 129)
  Four pamphlets from Mount Hope Farm, an experimental farm built by LSR's aunt and uncle, Alta Rockefeller and Ezra Parmalee Prentice. Brochures on Honey; Williamstown in the American Revolution; and suggested holiday gifts.
- The King's Message (George V), 1929 April 22 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  Copy of King George V's letter of thanks from Craigwell House.
- Receipt from John [Wethrell?] to James Faunce, Plymouth, 1761 May 1 (Box 12, Folder 131)
  Manuscript document. Provenance unknown, but it may have some connection to LSR's acquaintance, James L. Faunce. (See Faunce's letter to LSR, June 12, 1930, in box 5, folder 42, which mentions other documents from Plymouth, including references to persons named Faunce.
- Aviation Interests - Air Youth of America Pamphlets (3 Folders), 1941 (Box 12, Folder 132-134)
  Pamphlet numbers 1-24.
- Aviation Interests - Eastern Airlines, 1943-1945 (Box 12, Folder 135)
- Aviation Interests - Printed Material (2 Folders), 1931-1933, 1938-1947 (Box 12, Folder 136-137)
- Aviation Interests - Seaplanes, 1934, undated (Box 13, Folder 138)
- Economic Mobilization Course Notes, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 139)
- Naval Service - General (2 Folders), 1942-1945 (Box 13, Folder 140-141)
- Naval Service - Air Coordinating Committee, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 142)
- Naval Service - Airplane Production - Drawings, 1942-1945 (Box 13, Folder 143)
  Folder serves as a placeholder, as contents have been separated to oversized flat files.
- Naval Service - Airplane Production - Oversized Drawings, 1942 (Folder 1)
  Oversized drawings separated from Box 13, folder 143:
  Exploded Drawing of Major Breakdown PB2Y-3. Consolidated Aircraft Corporation, October 12, 1942. [22" x 34"]
  Production Breakdown of PBY5. Consolidated Aircraft Corporation, San Diego, November 17, 1942. [22" x 35"]
  Production Breakdown B-24-D. Consolidated Aircraft Corporation, San Diego, November 18, 1942 (old number was F32-1276). [22" x 35"]
- Naval Service - Airplane Production - Oversized Drawings, 1943-1944 (Folder 2)
  Oversized drawings and plans separated from box 13, folder 143:
  Proposal C54A Interior Navy (Preliminary Design), Douglas Aircraft Co., Santa Monica, drawing no. 5235504, November 2, 1943. [36" x 75"]
  Consolidated-Vultee Aircraft Corporation San Diego Division, Master Layout Plant 1, September 7, 1943 (PL-01). [35" x 49"]
  Consolidated-Vultee Aircraft Corporation San Diego Division, Master Layout Plant 2, September 14, 1943 (2PL-01). [34" x 58"]
  U.S. Naval Air Facility, Litchfield Park, Arizona, Proposed Layout. Navy Department, Bureau of Yards and Docks, November 6, 1943. [31" x 30"]
  Layout of G. A. C. Buildings and Airplane Parking and Pick Up Areas. Goodyear Aircraft Corporation, Arizona Div., Litchfield Park, Arizona, April 28, 1944. [44" x 41"]
- Naval Service - Airplane Production - Ryan Aeronautical Company, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 144)
- Naval Service - Air Technical Service Command Reports, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 145)
- Naval Service - Aviation - Herrmann Engine, 1942, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 146)
- Naval Service - Aviation - Printed Material, 1941-1945 (Box 13, Folder 147)
- Naval Service - Bureau of Aeronautics - Instructional Pamphlets (Nos. 1-10), 1942-1943 (Box 13, Folder 148)